Now, let's talk about searching and in linked list.
Consider this double anchored list that contains three nodes.
The first one at the address 1000, second at address 2000 and the third at 3000.
And the first node contains data 100.
The second contain data 200, and the third contains data 300.
And they are linked according to this configuration.
Now we are searching in this case for 300, so where is the note that contains the 300?
It the start by putting the VAD or the key that we are going to search for it inside a temporary variable
and start comparing that this temporary variable through all these nodes.
What is the note that contains this variable or this key?
If it is found, then it will return true or return the index of this note.
Otherwise, it will return false, or it will return minus one, according to what you have written.
The algorithm inside the function in this case, we are searching for number 300 inside this list.
The first one it will compare 300 was that data of the first known 100 does not equal to three.
So it moves to the next known.
Then it compares 300 with 200.
No, it's not the same.
It's not the case, and it moves to the next.
300 is equal to 300.
Yes, so it is this this is the case, so we have found the note that contains contains 300.
Otherwise, it will continue searching for till the end of the list if it contains this number that
we are searching for if returns true or the index of the value.
Otherwise it will return false if it does not contain or if that does not.
This doubling, if there's not funding this.
Key.
Let's make a new method.
It's called inthe search node, its type is in the returning type as end, so it is not Boolean, so
it will not return true or false, it will return one or whatever.
We will see them next couple of minutes.
So search node is the name of the method it contains as parameters.
Two things the first one is the struct node had, which is the pointer for the head and the end key.
What we are searching for.
So, OK, go and search the nodes for.
But we're what we are searching for the key.
So in this case, the key is equal to 300.
We are searching along this double link, at least along the nodes for key equal to 300.
Struck note, -- equal to had so go and create strike, no equal to head start from the beginning
because we are going to struggle to search the doubling list from the beginning to the end.
So go create a new temp at the head and put them does not equal to null.
If the data equal to the key, then return one.
OK, we start by this loop searching for the key.
If it is equal to the key that we are going to sit and equal to the data that that is contained inside
the node, then return one.
This is what we have told you.
It can return true or return one, depending on the returning type of the method that you are using.
No temp equals temp the next to move the cursor.
This is the trick that we have that we have seen along this course that in order to move the cursor
to the next, we use temp equal temp dot next.
This is the pointer how we move the pointer to the next one.
Otherwise, it will return minus one if it is not finding any thing.
OK, if there's not finding the key, so in our case, we found the key, so it was right to return
one if we are searching for 400 and these nodes are three, 100, 200 and 300.
We didn't have 400, therefore at those returning minus one.